A Guide to the Slade/Fitzhugh Family Papers, 1865-1932
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Slade/Fitzhugh Family Papers, 1865-1932
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 07-25
.25 linear feet
The Slade/Fitzhugh Family Papers span the years 1865-1932 and consist of receipts, correspondence, envelopes, a hand drawn land survey plat, and an unidentified photograph.
Unknown
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by Connie Stuntz, March 2017
Historical and Biographical Information
Connie and Mayo Stuntz acquired the papers in this collection in the late 1970s or early 1980s from a yard sale at a house in the community of Vale in Fairfax County, Virginia. The house, no longer standing, was located on Vale Road near what is today Silkwood Court, across from a field that was used as a landing strip for airplanes.
These papers originated from family members of the Fitzhugh and Slade families. Family members included in this collection are Amanda Gooding, Edwin C. Fitzhugh, Cook F. Slade, Mary Ann Fitzhugh, William Marbury Fitzhugh, and Julian F. Slade. They are all related and trace their genealogy back to a common ancestor, Col. Henry Fitzhugh.
Mordecai C. Fitzhugh (1767-1858) had nine children including Amanda Fitzhugh Gooding (1809-1893), Edwin C. Fitzhugh (1815-1880), and Juliana Fitzhugh Slade (1814-1861). All of Mordecai Fitzhugh’s children owned parcels of the Ravensworth tract after his death in 1858.
Juliana married William Otis Slade on April 22, 1847 and had a son named Cook F. Slade (1850-1937). Cook F. Slade was Amanda Gooding’s nephew, and was the executer of her will when she died.
Cook F. Slade married Sarah E. Fitzhugh (1859-1945) on June 2, 1887. Both of them descended from Col. Henry Fitzhugh (1723-1783). The couple had four children including Julian F. Slade (1889-1967). Sarah E. Fitzhugh’s sister was Mary Ann Fitzhugh (1840-1920) and her father was William Marbury Fitzhugh (1817-1878).
Scope and Content
The Slade/Fitzhugh Family Papers span the years 1865-1932 and consist of receipts, correspondence, envelopes, a hand drawn land survey plat, and an unidentified photograph. Subjects include Amanda Fitzhugh Gooding, Edwin C. Fitzhugh, William Marbury Fitzhugh, Mary Ann Fitzhugh, Cook F. Slade, and Julian F. Slade. All were descendants from Col. Henry Fitzhugh. Of particular note is a receipt from the E.M. Dunn store in Merrifield, Virginia and a letter from Elizabeth Watt owner of the Oak Hill mansion in Annandale, Virginia with a Burke’s Station post mark from 1903.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
MSS 06-27 Thomas Clowes Account Book
None
Index Terms
Fitzhugh Family; Fitzhugh, Edwin C. (1815-1880); Fitzhugh, Mary Ann (1840-1920); Fitzhugh, William Marbury (1817-1878); Gooding, Amanda Fitzhugh (1809-1893); Slade, Cook F. (1850-1937); Slade, Julian F. (1889-1967)
Container List
- Amanda M. Gooding - Receipt from Jonathan Roberts, Sheriff Fairfax County, 1865 State Taxes and County Levy, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Amanda M. Gooding - Letter from Thomas Moore, attorney, RE: Peter Gooding estate, 1886 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Amanda M. Gooding - Letter from Thomas Moore, attorney, RE: Peter Gooding estate, 1886 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Amanda M. Gooding - Letter from Thomas Moore, attorney, RE: Peter Gooding estate, 1888 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Amanda M. Gooding - Receipt from Peter Bazzel on renting Sleepy Hollow Farm [fragment], 1889 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amanda M. Gooding - Receipt from Robert Wiley Jr., 1892 tax bill, 1893 August 21 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Amanda M. Gooding - Receipt from Robert Wiley Jr., 1893 tax bill (paid by C.F. Slade), 1894 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Amanda M. Gooding - Land survey plat of Amanda Gooding's land near Columbia Pike, Falls Church, Va. "Smith to Throckmorton", Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Edwin C. Fitzhugh - Letter from J. Winston, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- William M. Fitzhugh - Letter to "Dollie", Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mary A. Fitzhugh - empty envelopes, 1901-1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mary A. Fitzhugh - Letter from Elizabeth Watt of Oak Hill, 1903 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mary A. Fitzhugh - Receipts from Storm & Sherwood Lewinsville Farm Dairy, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from Franklin Sherman, Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Loudoun County, Virginia, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Cook F. Slade - Letter from James M. Love, attorney, 1889 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt E.F. Cracker for building a house, 1893 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from Robert Wiley Jr., 1893 tax bill, 1894 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from Dr. W. Peyton Moncure, M.D., 1896 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from James M. Love, attorney, 1897 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from Robert Wiley Jr., 1896 tax bill, 1897 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from F.W. Besley, Fairfax County Treasurer, paid taxes, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from F.W. Richardson, Clerk of Fairfax County Court, deed release tax, 1898 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Cook F. Slade - Letter from F.W. Richardson, Clerk of Fairfax County Court, deed of release, 1898 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from F.W. Richardson, Clerk of Fairfax County Court, fee for land purchase from Henrietta Clowes (sister-in-law), 1899 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Cook F. Slade - Receipt from E.M. Dunn Store, Merrifield, Va., 1899 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Cook F. Slade - Letter from Moore, Barbour, and Keith, Attorneys, 1909 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Julian F. Slade - Summons from F.W. Richardson to testify in Commonwealth of Virginia vs. Hubert Sutton Jr., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Julian F. Slade - Statement for 1932 tax bill, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Unidentified photograph of man, child, and cat in front of house (possibly Cook F. Slade), Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)